翻译: 皮皮 MIA 扭头
- 叮咚  - 媽
- Ding dong. - Hey, Mom.
校对: 朽
Ellie 奶奶到了 她帶你去上學
Ellie! Grandma's here! She's gonna take you to school!
后期: 树树
你先別說話 是的 我今天要穿這件夾克
And before you say anything, yes, I'm wearing this jacket today.
那行吧 這是什么顏色 灰褐色嗎
Oh, if you say so. What is that, taupe?
压制: 凯撒
不是 這是英國軍隊的卡其色
No, it's British military khaki,
別擺出那副嘴臉了
and stop making that face because...
我不會換衣服的
I'm not changing it.
什么 你干什么 你現在那表情又是什么意思
What? What are you... what are you pointing that face at now?
沒什么啊 我就站在這兒
Nothing. I'm just standing here being a person,
看著臟兮兮的廚房
looking at a filthy kitchen.
Ellie昨晚應該洗盤子的
Ellie was supposed to do the dishes last night,
她肯定后來睡覺去了
but she must have fallen asleep.
中尉 您還真是紀律嚴明呢
Tight ship you're running, leftenant.
我不會整天聽你叨叨的
Well, I'm not hearing that all day.
- 鋪床了嗎  - 如果你不去我房間看 那我就鋪了
- Did you make your bed? - If you don't open my door, yes.
不好意思我睡過頭了 我們昨晚熬夜看了<西區故事>(歌舞片)
Sorry I overslept. We stayed up late watching Westside Story,
直到兇手跳完舞才睡
and didn't get to bed until after the dance murders.
被你擊中了
Oh, you got me!
Sean Harrison早間表演 謝謝
Thank you. The Sean Harrison breakfast players.
對了 我要用下你的信用卡
By the way, I need your credit
周末出去玩 要租一個滑雪板
card to rent a snowboard for my trip this weekend.
- 去拿吧 錢包在樓上  - 周末出去玩
- Yeah, my wallet's upstairs. - Weekend trip?
Ellie和她朋友第一次去滑雪噢
Ellie and some friends are going snowboarding for the first time.
我太激動了
I'm so excited!
天吶 她遺傳了你的叫聲
Oh, my God, she has your scream.
她睡過頭了 不干家務
So she oversleeps, doesn't do her chores,
你不但不禁足她 還給她信用卡
and instead of grounding her, you give her a credit card?
你應該去給芝加哥的懶漢做現場解說
You should do play-by-play for the Chicago bummers.
我就說說 她不把你當回事兒
I'm just saying, she doesn't take you seriously.
她可把我當回事兒了
She takes me seriously.
你就是嫉妒我是一個有趣的家長
You're just jealous because I'm fun,
而你呢
whereas you withheld
如果我不按字母順序整理好調味架 你就不讓我出去
approval if I didn't alphabetize the spice rack.
你可喜歡了
Oh, you loved it.
我確實喜歡
Yeah, I did.
但是我也可以對Ellie很嚴厲的 相信我
But I can be plenty tough on Ellie if I have to be. Trust me.
親愛的 你得馬上把這些盤子洗了
Honey, I need you to do these dishes now, please.
- 但是我上學要遲到了  - 確實是 你走吧
- But I'll be late for school. - That's valid. Off you go.
你軟得跟嬰兒屁股一樣
You're as soft as a baby's bottom.
Ellie 等下
Ellie, hang on.
家里的事情你也得多上點心
You're gonna have to chip in more around here.
隨便吧 晚飯見
Whatever. I'll see you at dinner.
不 這句話應該我對你說 因為今晚你來做飯
No, I'll see you at dinner, because tonight you're gonna cook.
如果你不做 周末就別想出去玩兒了
And if you don't, you don't get to go on your trip this weekend.
什么 太扯了吧
What? That's insane.
的確扯 但就這樣了 因為我說了算
That is insane, but it's happening now because I just said it.
行吧 我先上車
Fine, I'll be in the car.
還有 你那件新的灰褐色夾克純屬裝逼失敗
Oh, and your new taupe jacket is trying too hard.
這是英國軍隊的卡其色
It's British military khaki.
看到了嗎
Did you see that?
我態度強硬得很(我是個強受)
I am one bad-ass bottom.
那個 說出來就不對勁了
That, um... that came out wrong.
不管怎樣你都會讓她出去玩兒的
You're never gonna take that trip away.
因為這對她太重要了 最后肯定是這樣
It's too important to her. Here's what's gonna happen.
她今晚沒有做飯 但你還是不會怪她
There'll be no meal tonight, but you'll let her go anyway,
到時候她就知道你耳根子到底有多軟了
and then she'll know what a pushover you are.
我真是強忍著才沒把你掛到陽臺外頭
I am trying so hard not to dangle you off the balcony right now.
父親的瘋狂世界
第一季   第七集
電波誠譯
Ellie今晚如果沒做飯
So, either Ellie's gonna cook dinner tonight
她就別想去滑雪了
or she doesn't get to go on her ski trip this weekend.
我也能演壞警察啊 又不是沒演過
I can be bad cop. I've done it before.
在某一類派對上
At certain costume parties.
好吧 那確實是很"壞"的警察
Okay, that was naughty cop.
但是如果你禁足Ellie 你也得在家呆著了
But if you ground Ellie you're gonna have to stay in town,
我們不是要去Courtney的婚禮嗎
and we're supposed to go to Courtney's wedding.
天吶 我都忘了是這周了
Oh, my God, I forgot that's this weekend.
我真的需要你陪我去啊 她是我的老朋友了
I need you there. She's my oldest friend.
你知道我有多討厭她
You know how much I hate her.
你怎么突然開始對Ellie這么嚴厲了
How did you pick now to go all tough on Ellie?
還不是被我媽逼的
Because my Mom made me.
但她說得很對
But she's right.
Ellie應該多管管家里的事兒 做做飯
Ellie should pitch in more, make some meals.
她得知道 不是只要你餓了
She has to learn that food just
食物就這么神奇地出現了
doesn't magically appear every time you're hungry.
- 你的午餐  - 謝天謝地
- Your lunch is here. - Oh, thank God.
我餓死了 謝謝你Stavros
I'm starving. Thank you, Stavros.
- 28.50美金  - 好的
- $28.50. - Yeah.
我未來的女朋友Liz 你好
Hello, my future girlfriend, Liz.
不可能的 Stavros
It's not happening, Stavros.
你覺得不可能而已 對我來說早就開始了
For you. For me it has already begun.
我是"周末爸爸"的時候
Things were so much less
根本沒有這么多壓力
stressful with Ellie when I was the weekend Dad.
給 我得換些零錢
Here. I need some change.
Sean 你做得很棒 Ellie很愛你
You're doing fine, Sean. Ellie loves you.
我知道 但我希望她能一直這么喜歡我
I know, but I want her to keep
如果我禁足她 她會恨我的
liking me and if I ground her, she'll hate me.
教育孩子又不是拼人氣
Parenting is not a popularity contest.
你要給孩子們立好規矩
Children need boundaries.
恐怕還有別的人需要規矩
They're not the only ones.
比如說我就認識一個送外賣的
For instance, I know a certain
還以為自己是家庭心理咨詢師
delivery guy who thinks he's a family therapist.
Liz 我們要對我們的孩子更加嚴厲一點
Liz, we will be more firm with our children.
是的 我們會有分歧 但我們永遠不會把怒氣帶上床
Yes, we will argue, but we will never go to bed angry.
Sean 周五我能不能早點下班
Hey, Sean, I was hoping I could skip out early on Friday.
我的樂隊有個史上最大的演出
Our band's got our biggest gig ever.
當然 活兒留給我們 去追逐你的夢想吧
Sure, we'll cover for you. Follow your dreams, man.
如果你不會飛 還算什么鳥
Can't be a bird if you don't fly.
鴕鳥
Ostrich.
好吧鴕鳥確實不會飛 總之 你可以提前走
Okay ostriches don't fly, but the point is you can leave early.
- 謝謝 Sean  - 沒什么
- Thanks, Sean. - Yeah.
雞 火雞 企鵝
Chicken, turkey, penguin.
Sean 借一步說話
Sean, a word.
Sean 我聽到你要讓Hunter提前走
Sean, I overheard you giving Hunter time off.
干脆大家都像法國人一樣中午就走了
Why don't we all just skip out at noon like the French
用剩下的時間吃小三明治 搞外遇
and spend our days having tiny sandwiches and affairs?
我知道你是在諷刺 可是聽上去好棒
I know you're being sarcastic, but that sounds amazing.
Sean 作為你的導師
Sean, as your mentor...
- 導師  - 不客氣
- Mentor? - You're welcome.
我來教你兩招
I'm going to give you a piece
如何讓你的雇員更加高效
of advice to make your employees more productive.
你不能再那樣溺愛他們了
You have got to stop coddling them
要開始攪亂他們的頭腦
and start messing with their heads.
讓他們失去平衡 疑神疑鬼
Keep them off balance and paranoid.
我在考慮要不要炒你的魷魚
I'm thinking about firing you.
不 我不會的 是嗎 你可不知道
No, I'm not. Am I? You don't know.
Max 你玩心理戰術 是不能激發他們的潛力的
Max, you don't get the best out of people by playing mind games.
你要以誠待人 循循引導
You have to be honest and encouraging
就像我假想的父親 <天臺風云>里的Tim Gunn
like my imaginary Father, Tim Gunn, on Project Runway.
看來某人想和我打個賭啊
It sounds to me like someone would like to wager.
怎么就像要打賭了
How does that sound like that?
那就賭
You're on!
我打賭 我能讓Hunter
I will bet you that I can
自愿放棄他那寶貴的演出機會
get Hunter to voluntarily skip his precious gig
求我讓他整個周末都加班
and beg me to work all weekend.
為了讓這個賭更有意思
And just to make it more interesting,
我還會讓他往你身上扔一個你心愛的松餅
I will even get him to throw one of your beloved muffins at you.
現在是你的松餅了
Um, let's call that your muffin now.
而且我可不想把Hunter
And I don't wanna treat Hunter
當成實驗室的小白鼠一樣
like a lab rat in some deranged experiment.
很好 這事兒我來干
Oh, goody. That'll be my job.
你可以來定賭注
You may set the terms of the wager.
好吧
All right, fine.
如果你輸了 那就讓Hunter去演出
If you fail and Hunter goes to his gig,
然后你還得對辦公室的每個人說句好聽的話
then you have to say one nice thing to everyone in the office.
哈哈 真險惡
Oh, ha ha! Fiendish.
如果我贏了 你就得對每個人說句難聽的話
And if I succeed, you must tell one mean truth to everyone.
我們兩個都不能告訴Hunter
And neither one of us can tell
不然就沒有意思了
Hunter what we're doing, that would spoil the fun.
有意思
What fun?
沒錯
Exactly!
有意思 這事兒啊 多么有意思
What fun... we will have... when we do this!
Hunter
Hunter.
大H H炸彈 在這兒呢
Big H. The H-bomb. There he is.
我知道Sean讓你提前下班
I understand that Sean gave you some time off
去追逐你的音樂夢想
to pursue your musical dreams.
- 這沒什么問題吧 Max  - 當然沒問題
- I hope that's okay, Max. - Oh, absolutely.
夢想太重要了
Dreams are important.
不如你今天也別上班了 好好休息吧
In fact, why don't you take the rest of today off as well?
為什么呢
Why would I do that?
Sean一直都在和我說
Well... Sean's been telling
你的音樂對你來說有多重要
me how important your music is to you.
我希望你有足夠的時間來準備你的演出
I want you to have plenty of time to prepare,
所以快回去吧 寫一首像<We Built This City>這樣的
so go and write the next "We Built This City".
但是你從來不讓人提前走的啊 Max
But you never want people to leave early, Max.
不不 Sean已經說服我了
Oh, no, but Sean has convinced me
你需要像一只美麗的夜鶯一樣自由地飛翔
that you need to fly free like a beautiful songbird.
快走吧 走吧 不要回頭
So go. Go and don't look back.
我說了不要回頭
I said don't look back.
讓我剝開你的頭骨 啃噬你的心
Oh, I shall peel back your skull and snack on your mind.
媽 你在這兒干嘛呢
Hey, Mom, what are you doing here?
我過來看看Ellie有沒有做晚飯 看來她沒做
I came by to see if Ellie had made dinner. It appears she hasn't.
還好我包里有救急卷餅
Thank God I have an emergency burrito in my purse.
Ellie 下來
Ellie, come down here, please.
先別急著下定論
Let's not jump to conclusions.
也許她會捧著一個大火腿下來呢
Maybe she'll walk down the stairs carrying a giant ham.
你知道你現在陷入了一個怎樣的泥潭嗎
You see how you've boxed yourself in?
你不讓她去滑雪 她就沒轍了
You take away her trip, she'll be impossible.
如果你退縮了 她就知道她能隨心所欲了
If you back down, she'll know she can do whatever she wants.
最后她鼻子上的環會比浴簾上還要多
She'll end up with more rings in her nose than a shower curtain.
爸 奶奶 我知道要做晚飯了 馬上
Hi, Dad. Hi, Grandma. I know, dinnertime. I'm on it.
謝天謝地 看到了嗎
Oh, thank God. You see this?
我有責任感的好孩子 我完美的孩子
My responsible child. My perfect child.
我的Julia Child(美國名廚)
My Julia Child.
你在那兒瞎操心
And you were worried.
但我一直都知道 她會迎難而上
But I knew all along she would rise to the challenge,
付出努力 給我們做一頓美味的 自制的
put the effort in, and make us a delicious, homemade...
糟 她在用湯罐頭蒙混過關
Oh, crap, she's half-assing it with a can of soup, isn't she?
喂 喂
Hey, hey.
湯妹
Soupie!
- 怎么了  - 親愛的 抱歉
- Yes? - Honey, I'm sorry, okay,
開一罐爸爸留給感冒或者宿醉的湯
but opening a can of Daddy's special flu and hangover soup
可不算是做晚飯啊
does not count as making dinner.
所以
Oh! And so...
了結她
Finish her.
你的周末滑雪之旅
I'm afraid your weekend trip is...
不不 等下 你又沒告訴我這些規則
No, no, no, wait. No. You didn't tell me the rules.
我不知道我應該要做一頓大餐
I didn't know I was supposed to make some big, fancy meal.
你說得對 她說得對
You're right! She's right.
你不能因為她不知道這些規則就罰她
You can't punish someone who didn't know the rules.
我在新加坡嚼口香糖
That's how I got out of
就是用的這個理由逃過了鞭刑
getting caned for chewing gum in Singapore.
行了 再給你一次機會 明晚如果你不好好做一頓飯
Okay, one more chance. Tomorrow night, if you don't make a dinner
就別想去滑雪了
that takes some effort, your trip is off.
很公平 因為我才發現
Fair enough. Because I just realized
這是一罐燴番茄
this is a can of stewed tomatoes.
我知道 我知道 她搞砸了 但是我又沒告訴她規則
I know, I know, she blew it, but I didn't tell her the rules.
你是對的 你說得對
You're right, you're right.
她自己應該能想到的 但是我對她太嚴厲了
She should have figured it out, but I was tough on her.
可能沒那么嚴厲
Okay, maybe not that tough.
但是如果明晚
But if she doesn't make dinner
7:30她還沒做飯 那就別怪我不客氣 別想去玩兒了
tomorrow night by 7:30 sharp, that's it, no trip.
你不相信我嗎 明天親自過來瞧瞧
You don't believe me? Come tomorrow and see.
怎么了 還有事嗎
What? Something else?
我已經說得夠多了
I've said too much already.
"致Hunter Max上"
"To Hunter from Max"?
Max為什么要給我一盒松餅粉
Why would Max leave me a box of muffin mix?
打開看看
Open it.
也許里頭有個戒指呢
Maybe there's a ring inside.
Sean
Sean!
Max在我桌上放了盒松餅粉
Max left me a box of muffin mix on my desk,
昨天他還要我提前回去了
then he sent me home early yesterday.
他在搞什么鬼啊 我是不是現在要給他做松餅
What the hell's going on? Am I supposed to make him muffins now?
我不能告訴你 總之不要亂想
I cannot tell you. Just don't get paranoid.
- 所以確實有什么事情  - 我不能這么說
- So something is going on? - I cannot say that.
- 但是你就這么說了  - 我不能說
- But you did say that. - I cannot say.
- 發生什么了  - 好吧
- What's happening? - Okay.
我知道你很愛音樂
Look, I know how much you love music,
周五安心去演出就好了
so go to your gig on Friday.
但不管怎樣 不要沖我扔松餅
But whatever you do, do not throw a muffin at me.
我為什么要沖你扔松餅
Why would I throw a muffin at you?
我不能說
I cannot say.
我收到你的郵件了
I got your email.
你說如果Ellie今晚沒做晚飯
What do you mean if Ellie doesn't cook dinner tonight
你就要禁足她
you're gonna have to ground her
和她一起待在家里
stay at home with her this weekend
不能去婚禮了 是什么意思
and miss the wedding?
你哪里不懂
What part didn't you understand?
這可是我寫得最清楚的一封郵件了
Because it's arguably the clearest email I've ever written.
我懂
Oh, I understood it.
但是如果我只身一人去參加Courtney的婚禮
But if I have to go to Courtney's wedding without a date,
我就會上了新郎 把婚禮蛋糕當帽子戴在頭上
I'm going to screw the groom, wear the wedding cake as a hat,
然后在照相亭里懸梁自盡
and hang myself in the photo booth.
那張照片肯定很搞笑
That's gonna be a funny picture.
別這樣嘛 我需要你的幫助
Now, come on. I need your help.
你裝作是Ellie 讓我練習練習如何變得嚴厲
Pretend to be Ellie so I can practice being tough.
我干嘛要幫你
Why should I help you?
因為我們是朋友
Because you're my friend
這是作為朋友的分內事
and that's what friends do for each other?
好吧 Sean
All right, Sean.
你要我幫你 那我就幫
You want my help, you got it.
但是現在的小姑娘都心狠嘴毒
But teenage girls can be savages.
絕對不會留情面的 你有心理準備嗎
They fight dirty. You ready for that?
別廢話了 趕緊的
Enough trash talk. Let's just do this.
親愛的 我回來了 晚飯怎么沒做啊
Hi, honey, I'm home, and I don't see any dinner.
我做了 但是我給了無家可歸的人了
I made it, but then I gave
他才是更需要的人啊
it to a homeless person who needs it more.
有本事你證明我說謊啊
Prove I didn't.
她 她 她不會這么說的
She... she... she wouldn't say that.
我這才剛開始熱身呢 再來
Oh, I'm just getting warmed up. Again.
親愛的 我回來了 晚飯沒做 不許你去旅游
Hi, honey, I'm home and I don't see any dinner, so no trip.
爸 你扯什么淡
That's a bag of crap, Dad!
你個大肥淡
You're a big, fat bag of crap!
哇哦 她比我記憶中要兇狠很多嘛 我接著演
Wow, she's a lot more hostile than I remember, but, I'll play.
好吧 親愛的 我知道你很生氣
Okay, honey, I know you're mad...
是啊 我氣媽媽去紐約工作
Yeah, I'm mad because my Mom took a job in New York
我卻選擇留下來陪你 我現在腸子都悔青了
and I chose to stay here with you, and I totally regret it
因為你滿腦子都是各種破規矩
because all you care about are your stupid rules,
根本就不理解我
and you don't understand me at all.
現在你還要罰我
And now you have to punish me
因為你是奶奶的走狗
because you're Grandma's little bitch!
怎么了 你想哭了嗎 老爸現在是要哭了嗎
Oh, what's the matter? You gonna cry? Daddy gonna cry now?
天吶 是啊
Oh, my God. Yes!
哇哦 如果她像你這么說話 我就死了
Wow! If she says any of that, I'm dead.
所以就不要冒這個險了 和我去參加婚禮 會玩得很開心的
Well, then why risk it? Come to the wedding, we'll have fun.
好了 記住 你是來給我精神支持的
Okay, remember, you're here for moral support,
不要為了讓我陪你去婚禮
not to talk me into letting
就哄我放她一馬
Ellie slide so I can go to the wedding with you.
知道了 精神支持 "請攜親友"不就是派這用場的嘛 Sean
Got it. Moral support. That's what "Plus ones" do, Sean.
算你厲害
Way to keep swinging.
我聞到了
I smell...
空氣 我什么都沒聞到
Nothing. I smell nothing.
難以置信 她又沒做晚飯
I can't believe this. She didn't make dinner again!
Ellie
Ellie!
等一下 可能烤箱里會有東西
Wait! Maybe there's something in the oven.
Ellie
Ellie.
看 這燉菜看著就好吃
Oh, look. A beautiful casserole.
- 你這戲準備怎么演  - 烤到一半
- And your plan is... - Half-baked.
為了她這個虛擬的燉菜我已經盡力了
Which is more than I can say for her pretend casserole.
天吶 我現在只能當壞警察了
Damn it! Now I have to be bad cop.
她為什么要把我逼到這地步
Why does she put me in this position?
抱歉 出了點急事
Sorry, there was an emergency.
Sarah和她媽媽大吵了一架
Sarah got into this huge fight with her Mom.
她很難過 我沒法留她一個人在那兒
She was super-upset. I couldn't just leave her.
- Ellie 我們說好的  - 我知道 是我不對
- Ellie, we had a deal. - I know, and I blew it.
你現在做錯事了 所以不許你出去旅游
And you blew it, so you may not go on your trip.
- 我明白  - 不管你怎么反抗
- I understand. - No matter how much you fight me.
- 我沒想反抗  - 或者把責任推給你的朋友Sarah
- I'm not fighting you. - Or blame it on your friend Sarah.
- 我不怪Sarah  - 你不能
- I'm not blaming Sarah. - You may not...
去旅游嗎 我知道
Go on my trip? I know.
我幫你找了很多借口
I gave you plenty of chances.
Sean
Sean...
好像情況有點特別
I think something's happening here.
好像Ellie是在 承擔責任
I think Ellie's... taking responsibility.
不得不說 El 換我可不會這么輕易認錯的
I gotta say, El, this is not how I would have played it.
告訴我出了什么事
Tell me what's going on.
Sarah總是偷懶不做家務
Sarah's always getting out of doing her chores,
她的父母每次都會生氣 然后他們就會吵架
and her parents are always mad and fighting with her.
我不希望我們也這樣
I just don't want us to be like that.
既然我做錯了
I blew it, so I'm just gonna
那我就接受懲罰 爭取下次不再犯咯
accept my punishment and try not to screw up again.
天吶 我女兒最懂事了
Oh, my God, you're a fantastic child.
我也想做一個好相處的爸爸 但你一犯懶
I wanna be fun Dad, but when you slack off,
我就會變成很兇的爸爸 就像個
I turn into harsh Dad, which makes me feel like...
- 讓你失望了 老爸  - 是啊 "讓人失望的老爸"
- Sorry, Dad. - Yes! "Sorry Dad".
然后就變成猛灌咖啡酒和伏特加的老爸
Who then turns into Kahlua and vodka Dad.
不 我是說對不起
No, I meant I'm sorry.
我以后會主動做家務的 我保證
I'll do more without you having to bug me. I promise.
好
Good.
你周末去玩吧
You can go on your trip.
- 什么 真的嗎  - 是的 因為我相信你
- What? Really? - Yes. Because I believe in you.
嘿
Hey!
我們這周末都能出去玩啦
We all get to go away this weekend!
走 我們出去吃飯慶祝一下 我那份飯錢我自己付
Come on, let's go out and celebrate. My part of dinner's on me.
等一下 等一下 等一下 我們不能走 我媽正趕過來呢
Wait, wait, wait. We can't go out. My Mom's coming over.
如果被她發現你沒做晚飯
If she sees that you didn't cook dinner and I
而且我沒有關你禁閉 我要被她嘮叨一輩子
didn't ground you, I'll never hear the end of it.
你說得對 就算你死了都不會放過你
You're right. Even after you're dead,
她會寫張條子然后塞進你的棺材
she's gonna write a note and slip it in your casket.
沒錯 我覺得她會活得比你久
And, yes, I think she's going to outlive you.
這樣 我們點街轉角的那家希臘菜
All right, we'll order Greek food
就說是你做的
from the place on the corner and say you made it.
烤肉串 米飯色拉 這些你自己也能做的 對吧
Shish kebab, rice salad... you can make those things, right?
如果自動出現在門口 我能
If they show up at the door, I could.
兩天前你那"一定行"的精神去哪兒了
Where was that "Can do" Attitude two days ago?
看我給你做了啥
Look what I made for you.
松餅 給我的
Muffins. For me.
當然啦
You betcha.
你好大的膽子
How dare you!
這 這反應倒是出人意料啊
That... right there is an unexpected reaction.
我以為你給我松餅粉就是為了
I assumed that when you gave me the muffin mix, you...
我才不會給你什么松餅粉
I did not give you muffin mix.
我討厭松餅 我奶奶就是因為松餅過世的
I hate muffins. Muffins killed my Grandmother.
- 松餅怎么了  - 她在面包店工作
- They what now? - She worked at a bakery.
她往桶里倒藍莓的時候沒有站穩
She was adding blueberries to the vat, and she lost her footing.
有人說去世時不痛苦是件幸福的事情 但是
They say a better death is a peaceful death, but...
你把這話去跟一個肺里
Try telling that to an old woman whose lungs
都是藍莓和酵母的老人家說看看
are filling with blueberries and yeast.
但是盒子上有張紙條說是你送的啊 Max
But there was a note on the box that said it was from you, Max.
好一個栽贓嫁禍
A clever forgery!
很明顯 有人想設法讓你惹惱我
Obviously, someone is trying to get you to offend me
指望我炒你魷魚
perhaps so that I will fire you.
炒我魷魚
Fire me?
不過誰會想讓你被炒魷魚呢
Oh, no, but who would want to get you fired, and
而且 還有誰會知道我悲傷的蛋糕故事 沒人知道啊
who would know about my tragic muffin history? Nobody.
除了Sean
Except Sean.
- 不可能是Sean  - 不 不 不會 不會
- It couldn't be Sean. - No, no, no, no.
他很喜歡你 雖然
He loves you. Although...
雖然什么
Although what?
不 不 不 不 不 不可能是Sean
No, no, no, no, no! Couldn't be Sean.
- 雖然  - 什么啊
- Although... - What!
他的確說過要讓你自由地飛翔
Well, he does keep saying that you've got to fly free
去追逐音樂夢想
and pursue your musical dreams.
他可能覺得 只有逼你跳出鳥巢
Maybe he thinks the only way that you'll do that
你才會下定決心去追逐夢想
is if you're forced out of the nest.
但我不想離開這兒
But I don't want to leave the nest.
我也不想你離開
And I don't want you to.
但顯然 Sean想
But clearly... Sean does.
Sean錯了 我愛這兒
Well, Sean is wrong! I love the nest.
這兒有醫保還能拿到商品的七五折
The nest has health care and 25% off returned merchandise!
我知道 但是就像Sean說的 你遠遠高于這個地方
I know, but like Sean says, you are better than this place!
不 我和這里完全平等
No, I am not. I'm exactly equal to this place.
- 去你的表演  - 你不能強迫我
- Go to your gig! - You can't make me.
我哪兒也不去
I'm not going anywhere.
而且我要留下然后工作一整個周末
In fact, I'm gonna stay here and work all weekend!
很好
Good for you.
現在 把這些小松餅拿走
Now, get these muffins out of my sight.
Sean在我們倆中作梗實在讓我氣得想
I'm so mad at Sean for manipulating both of us, I might just...
沖他丟個松餅 一定很有快感 但
throw one at him, which would be enormously satisfying. But...
- 這不是我的戰爭  - 這不是你的 是我的
- it's not my fight. - No, it is not. It's mine.
記住
Remember!
不住在玻璃房子里的人 是扔松餅的
People who don't live in glass houses do throw muffins.
出自諺語Those who live in a glass house shouldn't throw stones.住在玻璃房子里的人不應該扔石頭
這話有理
It makes sense.
好了 現在廚房看起來像用過的了
Okay. Now the kitchen looks like a meal's been made.
好了 快 穿過去
Okay, quick, walk through this.
啊 Calvin Klein的烹飪謊言
Ah! Culinary lies by Calvin Klein.
- 進來 - 送餐
- Come in! - Delivery.
噢 Stavros 進來 快點
Oh, Stavros, my man, come in here, quick, quick!
我要把這些東西弄到盤子上
I gotta get this stuff on plates.
我媽十分鐘內就到了
My Mom gets here in ten minutes.
你們好 Sean 漂亮的Liz 任性的女兒
Hello, Sean, beautiful Liz, unruly daughter.
任性 你和別人說我什么了
Unruly? What do you tell people about me?
專注在你的工作上就好了 拜托
Just focus on your job, please.
這就是希臘經濟倒臺的原因
This is why the Greek economy's falling apart.
52.5美元
$52.50.
好的 給你
Great. Here.
門怎么是開的
Why is the door open?
媽 你來早了
Mom! You're early.
嘿 大伙兒 好消息 媽來早了
Hey, everybody, great news... Mom's early!
好香啊 這是誰
Ooh. Something smells good. Who's this one?
這是 呃
This? Um...
這是Stavros
This is Stavros.
希臘人
He is Greek.
他怎么在這兒
Uh huh. And why is he here?
因為
Because...
她是Liz的男友
He's Liz's boyfriend.
唔啪(希臘人常用嘆詞) 大家都開心了
Opa! We're all happy!
- 唔啪 - 唔啪
- Opa! - Opa!
真的 他是我男友
True! He's my boyfriend.
你可別打他主意哦 Lorna
Hands off, Lorna!
托Stavros的福 Ellie做了一頓希臘大餐
Ellie made this Greek feast in Stavros's honor.
- 都是我一個人做的 - 很棒嘛 親愛的
- All by myself. - Well, wonderful, darling.
Stavros 你和Liz交往多久了
So, Stavros, how long have you and Liz been dating?
這周四就滿六周了
Six weeks this Thursday.
她之前鞋跟卡在下水道上的橫欄里了
She got her heel caught in a sewer grate.
我救了她一命 然后現在
I saved her life and now...
我們成了情人
We are lovers.
這頓飯是為了犒勞Stavros的勇敢
While this dinner was to honor Stavros for his bravery,
但不幸的是 他得走了
unfortunately, he has to go.
我能留下的
I can stay.
Liz 過來
Liz, woman, come to me.
我想念你的愛撫
I miss your touch.
噢 Stavros
Oh, Stavros!
你真好
You're so great.
我喜歡看你穿吊帶衫的時候
I love it when you wear tank tops
帶子迷失在你肩發中的樣子
and the straps get all lost in your shoulder hair.
所以 你是干什么的 Stavros
So... what do you do, Stavros?
我是家庭心理咨詢師
I am a family therapist.
心理咨詢師 哇
A therapist? Wow.
所以你會對一個
So what would you say to a
從不想管教自己女兒的爸爸說什么呢
Father who never wants to discipline his daughter?
那你會對一個以為自己
And what would you say to a Mother
無比了解怎么當家長的媽媽說什么
who thinks she knows everything about parenting?
那你會對一個
And what would you say
女兒不做晚餐又不禁她足
to a man whose daughter doesn't cook dinner,
反倒叫了希臘菜外賣
but instead of grounding her because he can't,
還想裝作是自家做的菜的男人說什么
orders Greek food and tries to pass it off as homemade?
我會說 你該把手臂放下來了
I'd say it all means it's time for you to get your arm off me.
讓我付錢送你出門
And for me to pay you and send you on your way.
我只后悔點的不是中餐
My only regret is I didn't order Chinese food,
Ping Li會演好這出戲的
because Ping Li would have nailed this!
Liz 我們可以在蜜月的時候回味這件事
Liz, we will laugh about this on our honeymoon...
好吧 所以Ellie確實搞砸了
Okay, so Ellie did screw up,
但她承擔了責任 我為她驕傲
but she took responsibility, and I'm proud of her.
但按原計劃 你要禁她足
But the deal was you were supposed to ground her.
不 計劃是 她是我的女兒
No, the deal is she's my daughter,
我要做我認為對的事
and I have to do what feels right.
并且目前為止 計劃很有效 因為她是個很好的孩子
And so far, it's working, because she's a great kid.
你猜怎么著 我不會禁她足
So guess what. I'm not grounding her.
我要禁你足
I'm grounding you!
- 什么  - 你聽見了
- What? - You heard me.
你一個禮拜都不能給我建議
You cannot give me advice for one week.
這不公平 我不知道規則
That's not fair. I didn't know the rules.
什么 你說什么 你想要兩個禮拜
What? What was that? You wanna go for two weeks?
隨便了
Whatever.
- 你說什么  - 好吧
- Excuse me? - Okay, fine!
我一個禮拜之內都不會再提出任何意見
I will not voice an opinion about anything for one week.
太好了 開動吧
Excellent! Let's eat.
Ellie辛苦了一天 雖然不是為了這個
Ellie slaved all day not making this.
請期待不是我做的甜點吧
Wait till you see what I didn't make for dessert.
這周末的準備你做好了嗎
Are you all set for this weekend?
你帶上舞鞋了嗎
Did you pack your dancing shoes?
呃 我一直穿著呢
Uh... I'm never not wearing them.
你能跟我來我太開心了
I'm so happy you're coming with me!
現在可以開心地在那些單身妹子面前跳舞
Now dancing to all the single ladies
而不是在旁邊一邊看一邊腹誹了
will be fun instead of just a pointed observation.
噢 不 Hunter 我說過了不管你干什么
Oh, no. Hunter, I said whatever you do,
都別沖我扔松餅
do not throw a muffin at me!
那你就不該
Then maybe you shouldn't have
給我松餅粉 還讓我覺得那是Max送的
given me that muffin mix and made me think that
好讓我因為向他提起
it was from Max so that I would get fired for reminding him
他祖母悲劇的死而被炒魷魚
of his Grandmother's tragic batter death!
哇 Max真是厲害
Wow, Max has been busy.
噢 我贏了
Oh. I win.
而且如果你還記得 依照賭約
And if memory serves, the terms of our wager dictate
你要對每個人說一句殘酷的真話
that you now must tell everyone one mean truth.
來吧
Come, come.
打工仔們 圍過來
Workers... gather 'round.
Sean有些不太仁慈的真相
Sean has something mercilessly
要告訴這屋里的每個人
frank to say to everyone in this room.
好了 來吧
All right. Here we go.
Max 我覺得你染了胡子
Max, I think you dye your moustache.
閉嘴 散會
Shut up. Meeting adjourned. Disperse.
电波字幕组 欢迎您的加入
官方网站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@电波字幕组